Guide to the Stanford Oral History Project Interviews SC1017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Oral History Project interviews
1971-1995
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Historical Society
SC1017
16 Linear Feet (285 audiocassettes)
Scope and Contents note
The Stanford Oral History Project (SOHP), a joint effort of the Stanford University Archives and the Stanford Historical Society, began in 1978 as an extension of their efforts to collect, preserve and make available to researchers the historical record of the Stanford University community. These taped interviews and their transcriptions supplement the already strong collection of written and photographic materials in the University Archives, and provide a unique resource containing experiences and viewpoints not often found in traditional documents.
The oral history interviews in the SOHP collection are carefully planned historical documents which we hope will serve a wide range of scholarly interests. Five additional sets of oral history interviews are listed separately: a set of interviews with members of the early Aurora newspaper collective; a set of interviews with participants in Stanford's Community Committee for International Students (CCIS); a set of interviews conducted by Joan Bromberg of the American Institute of Physics for the Laser History Project; a set of interviews with graduates of the Stanford School of Nursing; a set of interviews with Stanford-associated "Silicon Valley" scientists (a component of the Stanford and the Silicon Valley Project); and a set of interviews with family and friends of Dr. Robert Reid Newell, professor in the School of Medicine.
For most of the interviews, a typed transcript, edited for accuracy by both interviewer and narrator but otherwise unchanged, is available.
Arrangement note
The interviews are arranged in seven series: 1. Stanford Oral History Project Inteviews; 2. Aurora Interviews; 3. Community Committee on International Studies Interviews; 4. Laser History Project Interviews; 5. Stanford Nurse Alumnae Interviews; 6. Silicon Valley Project Interviews; and 7. Dr. Robert Reid Newell Interviews.
Access to Collection
Administrative files series is closed for 50 years from date of creation. Otherwise the collection is open for research use.
Interviews.; Oral histories.; Stanford University -- History.; Stanford Historical Society; Hofstadter, Robert; Irwin, Will; Manson, Clara; Newell, Alan.; Mendelowitz, Daniel M.; Purdy, Ann Peril.; Mellott, Annette; Mitchell, Sidney; Merriman, Sue; Mercer, Michelle; Dwight, Herbert H.; Mitchell, J. Pearce.; Millar, Kay; Ichihashi, Yamato; Krebs, Ruby; Krauskopf, Konrad; Leu, Anna Jagels; Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson); Lane, Joane; Brandin, Alf E.; Lewis, Janet; Levison, Robert Mark; Lutz, Ralph Haswell; Peck, Templeton.; Press, Harry.; Price, Harry.; Proctor, Elizabeth; Veblen, Thorstein (Thorstein Bunde); Qualls, Katherine; Rosenzweig, Robert M.; Rempel, Robert; Ryan, Harris J. (Harris Joseph); Colby, Edward E. (Edward Eugene); Reynolds, Harry B.; Mumford, Lewis; Murphy, Michael H.; Norman, Ruth; Nunan, Craig; Franklin, H. Bruce (Howard Bruce); Ferguson, Charles A. (Charles Albert); Packard, Martin E.; Page, Virginia; Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard); Clark, Esther Bridgman.; Pearson, Daryl H.; Hobart, J.; Hewlett, William R.; Hawes, Josephine; Hänsch, Theodor; Hutchinson, Eric.; Howard, Mildred Dye; Hoover, William; Harder, Virginia; Green, Cecil Howard; Hansen, Ralph Waldo; Haswell, Roka; Hastorf, Barbara; Harwood, Lee; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Keesling, Francis V.; Johnston, Beatrice; Willis, Bailey; Kaplan, Leah; Kershaw, Henrietta; Keyes, Pat; Kendrick, Betty Roth; Keohane, Nannerl; Freeman, Szebelski ("Sibby"); Packard, David, 1912-1996; Snyder, Rixford K. (Rixford Kinney); Jacobson, David S.; Crothers, George E. (George Edward); Jahns, Richard H.; Johnson, Melba Beard; Beard, Rodney.; Johnson, Olivia; Jones, Henry.; Jensen, Margaret; Jessup, R.Bruce; Welis, Alison; Treat, Payson J. (Payson Jackson); Weinreich, Max; Whitaker, Virgil; Whitaker, Douglas.; Wallingford, Janice; Webster, David Locke; Warnlof, Mary Ann; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982; Vickers, Joseph; Torf, Adrienne; Deal, Bruce E.; Williams, Gertrude; Wright, Mabel; Wilbur, Dwight; Wilbur, Mary Sloan; Dodds, John W. (John Wendell); Barclay, Thomas S. (Thomas Swain); Linvill, John G.; Silber, Bernice; Siegman, A.E.; Schofield, Mary; Schawlow, Arthur B.; Rusmore, Jean; Ruddock, K.; Rothert, Harlow Phelps.; Roth, Almon.; Roth Sisters; Roseberry, Louis H.; Roesler, Fran; Tresidder, Donald Bertrand; Chandler, Loren Roscoe ("Yank"); Ricker, Christine; Stuart, Graham.; Swank, Raynard C.; McDowell, John Ezra.; Stanford Oral History Project.; Spears, Virginia; Spaeth, Sheila; Sloss, Leon.; Smith, Stephanie; Skarin, Miriam; Engelbart, D. C., 1925-2013; Slaven, Helen Adell; Bailey, Thomas Andrew; Cohen, Stanley N.; Hanna, Paul Robert; Hansen, W. W. (William Webster); Bacon, Harold; Bacon, Rosamond Clarke.; Ceideburg, Holly Hansen.; Hall, Harvey.; Keen, A. Myra (Angeline Myra); Baer, Carolyn; Dornbusch, Sanford M.; Ashley, Celeste; Applewhite, Liat; Angell, Thomas; Walker, Frank Fish; Anderson, Reid; Terman, Lewis Madison; Alway, Robert; Bliss, James; Blake, Marilyn; Berry, Chester; Bark, Eleanor; Wiggins, Ira L. (Ira Loren); Dinkelspiel, Lloyd W.; Bancroft, Kim; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian); Abramowitz, Carrie; Crosten, William Loren; Cuthbertson, Kenneth.; Crowell, Peggy; Davis, Paul H.; Davis, Margo.; Davis, Paul; Rawlings, John; Denhard, Alice; Demoit, Debby; Dodds, Marjorie.; Dutton, Dorothea; Yalom, Marilyn; Botsford, Margaret; Bowes, Ruth Garland; Boyd, Harold; Ringressy, Grace.; Dinkelspiel, John.; Bretall, Norah; Almond, Dorothea K.; Brown, Phyllis; Bush, Vannevar; Carley, Lucille O.; Robinson, Edgar Eugene; Stanford Historical Society; Chuck, Frank Y.; Kriss, Joseph P.; Fishman, Joshua A. (Shikl); Cline, Laura; Abrams, Herbert L.; Craig, Phyllis H.; Richards, Victor.; Glover, Frederic O.; Adams, Ephraim Douglass, 1865-1930; Gillingham, Jane; Gonzales, Leenda; Sterling, J. E. Wallace (John Ewart Wallace); Goldsborough, John; Goheen, John; Goff, Harry And Kay; Goff, Harry And Kay; Gunst, Morgan A.; Guerard, Albert.; Grundt, Carolyn; Hall, Marion Dwight; Guthrie, Luell Weed; Stolz, Lois Meek; Varian, Russell Harrison; Dwight, Herbert Mcgilvray; Edgar, Jean; Bloch, Felix; Edwards, Paul C. (Paul Carroll); Farnsworth, Paul; Hargadon, Fred; Fischel, Eleanor; Fejos, Paul.; Lyman, Jing; Gibson, Helen
- Stanford Oral History Project, Series 1
  - Abramowitz, Carrie, 1977 Apr 27, May 2; 1_3; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Biographical/Historical note
    Known primarily for her sculpture, artist Carrie Abramowitz and her husband, Professor Moses Abramowitz, were a part of the Stanford community for many years.
    Scope and Contents note
    Interview by Margo Davis, donated to the SOHP; 180 minutes
  - Almond, Dorothea, 1987 Aug 11, 25; 4_6; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    One of the directors of child care at Stanford, Mrs. Almond discusses the history of child care at Stanford from the beginning. Interviewed as part of the faculty spouses series.
    Interview by Mimi Webb; transcribed
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Alway, Robert, 1980 Apr 1; 7_8; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Professor of pediatrics, Stanford Medical School; Head, Pediatrics Department; Dean of the Stanford Medical School, 1958-1964; and Medical Director of Stanford Hospital until his retirement in 1977.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover; transcribed, 55 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Angell, Thomas, 1985 Jun 29; 9_10; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Thomas Angell, class of 1915, was the son of Dr. Frank Angell, pioneer Stanford faculty member, noted psychologist, and active leader in Stanford athletic affairs. Thomas Angell made a career as an insurance broker in San Francisco.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover; transcribed, 28 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Ashley, Celeste, 1984 Apr 14; 11_12; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Actress, teacher of creative dramatics, and theater librarian. In charge of drama collection, Stanford Library, 1953-1976.
    Interview by Sara Timby; transcribed, 21 pages
  - Bacon, Harold, 1987 Jan 23
    Professor of Mathematics Emeritus, at Stanford from 1936 until his retirement in 1972; received his A.B. (1928), A.M. (1929) and Ph.D. (1933) degrees from Stanford, all in mathematics. Professor Bacon and his wife Rosamund moved into the house at 565 Mayfield in 1930.
    Their home, a Stanford historical landmark, was built by Mrs. Harriet Dunn, cousin of Harold's father and a friend of Jane Stanford.
    Interview by 'R.L.'
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Bacon, Rosamund, 1981 Mar; 13_14; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Her interview is titled "Life on the Row;" she discusses what life was like living on the Row in the late 1920s.
    Rosamund Bacon received an A.B. degree from Stanford in 1930 in History and an A.M. degree in 1932. She was director of the Union, which included the Row.
    Interview by Karen Porter
  - Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1978 Jul; 15_16; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Margaret Byrne Professor of American History and American diplomatic historian, Dr. Bailey received his A.B. (1924) and Ph.D. (1927) from Stanford, joining the Stanford faculty in 1926. He became emeritus in 1968.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover; transcribed and bound, 66 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Barclay, Thomas Swain, 1980 Feb; 17_19; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Professor of political science at Stanford since 1927, became emeritus in1957. Professor Barclay played an active role in the Democratic Party at both the local and national levels, serving as delegate or alternate to three conventions and presidential elector in 1944. He died in 1993.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover and Harry Press; transcribed and bound, 70 pages
    Oral histories.; College teachers.; Student life.; Sororities.; College teachers -- Political activity.; United States -- Politics and government.; Treat, Payson J. (Payson Jackson); Barclay, Thomas S. (Thomas Swain); Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Walker, Frank Fish; Stuart, Graham.; Bailey, Margery; Adams, Ephraim Douglass, 1865-1930; Ichihashi, Yamato; Stanford University. School of Medicine; Veblen, Thorstein (Thorstein Bunde); Sterling, J. E. Wallace (John Ewart Wallace); Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976; Stanford Oral History Project.; Dornbusch, Sanford M.; Terman, Lewis Madison; Stanford Associates.; Press, Harry.; Robinson, Edgar Eugene; Lutz, Ralph Haswell; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian); Whitaker, Douglas.; Tresidder, Donald Bertrand; Glover, Frederic O.
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Bark, Eleanor, 1987 Mar-May; 20_22; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    A graduate of Stanford (1935) and member of the Stanford community from 1947 until her death in 1999, Mrs. Bark was Palo Alto City Historian (1956-1959) and worked in the Graduate Division at Stanford (1959-1970). Her interview covers her experience as a volunteer and a staff member and life as a faculty wife.
    Interview by Joanne O'Donohue; transcribed
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Bowes, Ruth Garland, 1981 Feb, May
    Received her A.B. (1920) and M.D. (1925) from Stanford, and later served as an assistant in the Department of Pediatrics and Medicine.
    Interview by Diana Bowes; transcription only
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Boyd, Harold, 1980 Sep; 23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Formerly Associate Dean of Student Affairs (1969-1980), and Director of the Medical Fund in the Office of Development (1980-1995). Mr. Boyd has been a strong spokesman for equal rights for blacks in both academic and administrative affairs.
    Interview by Marion Hall and Harvey Hall; transcribed, 22 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Brandin, Alf
    - 1987 Jun 12, 24_28; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
      Business Manager of the University under Presidents Tresidder and Sterling, Alf Brandin oversaw the development of the Stanford Industrial Park and the Stanford Shopping Center. As an athlete, Brandin played on the Stanford Rose Bowl team of the 1930s and was one of the legendary "Vow Boys."
      Interview by Robert de Roos; transcribed
      - Transcript (Box 8)
    - 1990 Sep 6, 282; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
      Scope and Contents
      Interviewed by Fred Glover for Donald Tresidder book project.
  - Ceideberg, Holly, 1981 Apr 17; 29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    This tape is a speech by Mrs. Ceideberg to the Stanford Historical society entitled "Recollections of Sam McDonald." She worked with Sam McDonald on the preparation of his book, Sam McDonald's Farm.
    Stanford, Class of 1940.
  - Chandler, Loren Roscoe ("Yank"), 1979 Jan 22; 30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Professor of Surgery Emeritus, Chandler was Dean of the Stanford Medical School from 1933 to 1953, and a blunt-spoken participant in important phases of Stanford medical history. Dean Chandler died in 1982.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover; transcribed, 21 pages, 2 page biography
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Chuck, Frank Y., 1981 May
    Earning his A.B. in Chemistry (1922), Chemical Engineering degree (1923), and Ph.D. in Chemistry (1925) from Stanford, Dr. Chuck was an active member of Stanford's Chinese student community.
    Interview by Marion Hall and Harvey Hall; transcribed, 20 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Clark, Esther Bridgeman, 1979-1980; 31_35; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Dr. Clark began her medical practice in 1927 as the only pediatrician between San Mateo and San Jose. The daughter of Stanford professor Arthur B. Clark, she attended the Campus School, and later received her B.S. (1921) and M.D. (1925) from Stanford. She was one of the founding physicians of the Palo Alto Medical Clinic as well as of the children's Health Council in Palo Alto.
    Interview by Marion Hall and Ann Chase; transcribed, 39 pages. A second interview by Phyllis Johnson; transcribed
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Cohen, Stanley N., 1995; 278_295, 307_318; 30 audiocassette(s) (Box 13, Box 12)
    Biographical / Historical
    Stanley N. Cohen is a physician and researcher, who has studied the biology of bacterial plasmids (circular deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) molecules that replicate independently of the bacterial chromosome), and helped explain the mechanisms underlying the control of cell growth and gene expression in higher organisms. Cohen is best known for his work with geneticist Herbert W. Boyer, in which they became the first scientists to transfer a gene from one species to another, proving that the transplanted gene could function normally in its new home.
    Cohen and Boyer worked only a few dozen miles from each other, Cohen at Stanford and Boyer at the University of California at San Francisco, but did not meet until both men attended a conference on plasmids in Honolulu in the spring of 1972. Discovering their similar concerns, they had a late-night conversation over hot pastrami and corned beef sandwiches at a Korean deli on Waikiki Beach, and began collaborating. In just four months, using Boyer's methodology, they were able to successfully introduce foreign DNA into a bacterial plasma, and using Cohen's methodology, they were able to subsequently insert this modified plasmid into bacteria. Because bacteria divide very rapidly, their work allowed the genetic "manufacturing" of engineered drugs and hormones, leading to the multi-billion dollar biotechnology industry.
    Appointments: Kwoh-Ting Li Professor at the School of Medicine (1993 - present) Professor of Genetics, School of Medicine (1977 - present) Professor of Medicine, School of Medicine (1975 - present)
    Education: M.D., University of Pennsylvania, Medicine (1960) B.S., Rutgers University, Biological Sciences (1956)
    Professional: Guggenheim Fellowship (1975) Roche Institute V.D. Mattia Award (1977, with Herbert W. Boyer) Lasker Award (1980) ACS Marvin J. Johnson Award (1981) Wolf Prize in Medicine (1981) National Medal of Science (1988) National Medal of Technology and Innovation (1989) AGU Robert E Horton Medal (1993, with Boyer) Lemelson-MIT Prize (1996, with Boyer) National Inventors Hall of Fame (2001) Shaw Prize in Life Science and Medicine (2004, with Boyer) National Institutes of Health Division of Research Resources (1970-74) Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences Editorial Board American Association for the Advancement of Science (1994) American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1978) American Cancer Society American Philosophical Society (2006) American Society for Biochemistry and Molecular Biology American Society for Microbiology (1992) American Society for Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics Association of American Physicians Genetics Society of America Institute of Medicine (1988) Lasker Foundation Awards Jury (1981-88; 2006-present) National Academy of Sciences (1979) National Research Council Committee on Biotechnology Nomenclature Wellcome Trust Experimental Therapeutics Advisory Committee (1992-97)
    - Transcript, 1 computer file(s) (pdf)
  - Colby, Edward E., 1981 Feb 14; 36_38; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Music Librarian at Stanford and Archivist, Archive of Recorded Sound.
    Interview by Carol Bradley for the Collection of Source Materials Documenting the History of Music Librarianship in the United States, house at SUNY Buffalo.
  - Craig, Phyllis H., 1986 Nov-1987 Jan; 39_42; 4 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    Member of the Stanford community from 1961 until her death in 2006, Mrs. Craig was a childcare consultant and co-director, Childcare Resource Center. Interviewed as part of the faculty wives series.
    Interview by Mimi Webb; transcribed.
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Crosten, Wlliam Loren, 1983 Mar, 1984 Mar; 43_47; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Chairman of the Music Department at Stanford, 1946-1973, Professor Crosten speaks of the many developments in the programs, facilities and repertoire of the department and its faculty.
    Interviews by Frederic O. Glover.
  - Davis, Paul, 1979 Nov; 48_50; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    A national1y known consultant on college fund-raising, Mr. Davis graduated from Stanford in electrical engineering in 1923, managed the men's athletic program (1922-1925) and later returned to campus in 1936 as Director of the Stanford Fund. He was named General Secretary in 1941, 1eaving that post in 1946 to serve under Dwight Eisenhower as General Secretary and Vice President of Columbia University. In 1950, he became an independent consultant, and remained in that work until his death in 1981.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover and Paul R. Hanna; transcribed, 57 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Dinkelspiel, John, 1988 Jul 1, Sep 5; 270_273; 4 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Dodds, John Wendell, 1981 Feb; 51_53; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Professor of English from 1937 until his death in 1989 and first dean of the School of Humanities (1942-1948). Professor Dodds also served as director of the war-time Program in Far Eastern Areas and Languages, and of Humanities Special Programs (1948-1967) when the School reorganized as the School of Humanities and Sciences in 1948. Named Jackson Eli Reynolds Professor of Humanities in 1962, Professor Dodds specialized in the literature of 19th century England.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover and Paul R. Hanna; transcribed and bound, (70 pages) with a 30-page appendix, "A Few Notes Toward a Recollection" by J.W. Dodds
    Interviews.; Oral histories.; Hanna, Paul Robert; Bailey, Marjorie.; Willis, Bailey; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Wenner-Gren Foundation; Stanford Oral History Project.; Dodds, Marjorie.; Franklin, H. Bruce (Howard Bruce); Stanford University. School of Humanities; Fejos, Paul.; Guerard, Albert.; Glover, Frederic O.; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian); Mumford, Lewis; Stanford University. Department of English; Dodds, John W. (John Wendell); Tresidder, Donald Bertrand
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Eurich, Alvin C., 1980 Oct 6-7; 57_59; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Professor of Education at Stanford and Vice President under Dr. Donald B. Tresidder, Professor Eurich became acting president of the University, 1948-1949, following President Tresidder's death. He became Chancellor of the state University of New York in 1949.
    Interview by Frederic O. Glover and Paul R. Hanna; transcribed and bound, 77 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Farnsworth, Paul, 1978 Jan 10; 60; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Professor of Psychology, 1925-1964. Professor Farnsworth discusses the early years of the Psychology Department at Stanford, beginning with the founding of the University.
    Interview by Ernest Hilgard; transcribed, 14 pages
  - Fishman, Joshua, 1997 Dec
    Yiddish secular schools.; Oral histories.; Jews -- Social life and customs.; Yiddish language.; Jewish day schools.; YIVO.; Yiddish Scientific Institute.; Ferguson, Charles A. (Charles Albert); Fishman, Joshua A. (Shikl); Rawlings, John; Stanford Oral History Project.; Weinreich, Max
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Freeman, Szebelski ("Sibby"), 1980 Aug; 61_62; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Member of the Associated Students of Stanford University Council of Presidents, 1979-1980, Sibby Freeman entered Stanford in 1967. He "stopped out" briefly to do draft counseling for the Eldridge Foundation and other community work. He returned to Stanford in 1973 and received his A.B. in Anthropology and M.A. in 1981.
    Interview by Harvey Hall; transcribed, 30 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Goheen, John, 1987 Jan 20; 63; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Professor of Philosophy at Stanford, 1950-1972; University Ombudsman, 1974-1985.
    Interview by Judy Adams; transcribed
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Green, Cecil H., 1989 Feb; 64_67; 4 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Guthrie, Luell Weed, 1978 Feb; 68_69; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    Former head of the Department of Women's Physical Education (1956-1968), Professor Guthrie joined the Stanford faculty in 1936 and is noted for her activities in Women's intercollegiate tennis and skiing.
    Interview by Margo Davis; donated to the SOHP; transcribed, 52 pages
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Hall, Harvey, 1980 Jan; 70; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    A graduate of UCLA, Mr. Hall taught at Sequoia High School (1932-1950) before coming to Stanford as assistant registrar (1948-1949). He served as registrar of Stanford University (1950-1970) and Ombudsman (1970-1972). Mr. Hall received the Dinkelspiel Award for service to undergraduates in 1971, and was elected president of the American Association of Collegiate Registrars and Admissions Officers (1970).
    Interview by Jeff Littleboy
  - Hall, Marion Dwight; Dwight, Herbert McGilvray, 1979 Nov; 71; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    "Growing up at Stanford, 1906-1925." As children, Marion and her brother Herbert lived on campus with their grandparents, Mr. and Mrs. John D. McGilvray. (McGilvray was a stone contractor responsible for construction on many major university buildings.) Marion received her A.B. (1922) and A.M. (1923) from Stanford. Herbert received his A.S. (1925) from Stanford. The interview covers their childhood and life as students at Stanford. Hall's husband of 62 years was Stanford Registrar Emeritus Harvey Hall.
    Interview by Harvey Hall
  - Hansen, Ralph Waldemar, 1979 Aug 21-24; 72_73; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)